<Document>
  # Rule 0: Community Expectations
  Administrators reserve the right to disregard or modify the application of specific rules at their discretion if they deem it in the best interest of the current round, server, or player base as a whole.  When applying this rule, permission must be sought from the highest-ranking administrator currently online.  Any use of Rule 0 places full responsibility on the administrator for the actions taken regarding their rule modification.

  Rules are applied as intended.  Every single instance of rule-breaking cannot be defined in writing; therefore, rule application depends on the administration's interpretation of their intent.

  If an administrator gives you an instruction or makes a ruling, do not argue with the administrator and follow the instruction/accept the ruling. You may file a complaint against the administrator on the forums/Discord or contact their supervisor directly if you disagree with the ruling after the round has ended. Arguing with administration can result in punishment. Administrators are volunteers and will not tolerate toxicity or any other hostility while performing their duties.

  General behavioral expectations for community members. Unless explicitly stated otherwise, these rules apply to all areas of the community.
  - Don't be a jerk.
  - Do not make threats (even as a joke) in OOC.
  - Use common sense to determine if "it" is acceptable or not.
  - This is not an exhaustive list, only the most important elements.
  - This extends to in-character (IC) use of brainrot. You shouldn't be using "lol," "ty," or other such abbreviations.

  ## Racism and Intolerance
  - Using slurs OOC on the server will result in a ban.
  - Racism of any kind is strictly prohibited and will not be tolerated.
  - Being sexist or simply bigoted is unacceptable, and action will be taken to correct such behavior.
  - Usernames that administrators deem racist, sexist, etc. are not permitted.

  ## Stereotypes
  - Playing a character based on a particular stereotype is permitted; however, playing a character that is a racial, religious, or cultural caricature is prohibited.
  - Senior Staff or the highest-ranking alternative official reserve the right to declare particular stereotypes as racially, religiously, or culturally offensive.

  ## Spam
  - Spamming chats is not permitted.  This includes copypastas, macro spam, and anything else that intentionally creates large volumes of message content.
</Document>
