<Document>
  # Rule 2: Roleplay
  The server has a medium roleplay standard. Play as a believable character. Treat your character as a separate entity from yourself as a player. Your character’s actions, emotions, and knowledge must be based on the character’s experience — not your real-life experience or OOC knowledge. Low-effort behavior that does not fit your character or the setting (memes, silly IC copypasta spam, etc.) is not acceptable. Character development may occur over multiple rounds, but each round is considered a soft reset — you may have past mission experience (not involving Xenomorphs), but your character has not permanently died or fled the Almayer before. Maintain roleplay standards.

  Major disruptions that interfere with the normal flow of the round at the start of the game are not allowed (this includes but is not limited to: large fights, lethal conflicts, brawls during briefing, riots, brig break-ins, heavy equipment theft, and obstructing players trying to prepare for deployment).

  ## Human Roleplay Standards

  ## Arrests and Riots on the Ship
  - Starting a riot over an arrest before first deployment will be treated as sabotage, and administrators will intervene. You should not lynch the MPs or throw away your Marine career just because someone got arrested.

  ## Sanity
  - All personnel enlisted in the USCM are mentally stable and physically fit for duty. They will not abandon their posts or turn against the USCM without strong justification.
    - For example: A maintenance technician would not dismember corpses in a trash compactor.
  - The USCM is aware of most human-based threats (SPN, KOF, PMC forces, etc.) as well as general knowledge about Xenomorph hive structure.

  - If an infected marine can still be saved, you are expected to try, rather than wall them in and wait for the larva to emerge.

  ## Ship Modifications
  - Disassembling the ship should not occur before first landing and confirmed contact. Marines would not dismantle a military ship over an unconfirmed distress signal.
    - This includes removing briefing room chairs, but does not include barrels or crates scattered in maintenance storage.
    - This also includes removing vending machines from the ship when there is no practical need. You would not take half the medical bay with you into combat.

  ## Survivors
  - Survivors are allowed more freedom of behavior due to possible trauma from the Xenomorph attack. They may roleplay PTSD, paranoia, or other psychological effects.
  - Survivors cannot be hostile to Marines unless they belong to a hostile faction.
      - Survivors should not deliberately harm other survivors.
  - Survivors should not assault the hive while it is still in its early development stage (first ~10 minutes).
  - Most survivors do not have combat training (unless their background suggests otherwise, e.g., prison guard, PMC, etc.), and therefore cannot fight alongside Marines effectively.
  - Survivors generally cannot perform the roles of department heads, pilots, or ship officers.
  - Survivors have sent a distress signal and must visit the Almayer at least once to report.
      - After this, they may either return to the colony or remain on the Almayer and surrender their weapons to the MPs.

  ## Command
  - The Operation Commander must follow standard operating procedure.
    - Example: You MUST hold a briefing and MUST attempt to establish defenses around the primary landing zone.

  ## Identification Cards
  - ID cards should only be taken for roleplay reasons (e.g., taking the Executive Officer’s ID from a corpse to authorize evacuation). If you find an ID from a living or revivable player, you should make reasonable effort to return it unless your character has valid justification not to.
    - You should not grant yourself or others extended access unless there is a staffing shortage or exceptional necessity.
    - You should not issue yourself or others (semi-)full-access IDs.
  - The death or absence of senior officers is a valid reason to grant necessary access to continue the operation.
    - Requests for missing personnel are valid reasons to authorize access to supplies, etc.

  ## Xenomorph Roleplay Standards

  ## Hive Mind and Purpose
  - Xenomorphs lack individual free will. They operate as a collective and obey the Queen to expand the hive.
  - They are not friendly and do not negotiate.
    - Separate hives must be hostile toward all factions, including each other (unless an event explicitly states otherwise).
    - Xenomorphs should not destroy synthetic life unless it interferes with them. The Queen may override this as needed.

  ## Larva
  - Larvae should remain in safe areas and avoid frontlines.
  - If Marines are about to reach the hive core or too few Xenos are available, leaving the hive as a larva to assist is acceptable.
  - Larvae should not attempt to board the Almayer via dropship.
    - Larvae are not scouts and should not search for survivors or perform recon.

  ## Queen
  - The Queen may devolve Xenomorphs who fail to meet hive standards. Devolution must not be done as a joke or without reason.
  - The Queen may devolve Xenomorphs to encourage certain castes (e.g., Boilers for defense).
      - If initial attempts fail, the Queen should not devolve the majority of the hive for a single caste — the number of devolutions should be reasonable.
      - The Queen must ensure another Xenomorph can evolve into the required caste before devolving others.
  - The Queen may use devolution as punishment for severe roleplay violations (e.g., griefing or deliberate disruption).
  - The Queen may not force specific sub-branches, strains, or mutations without valid justification.

  ## Xenomorphs on the Almayer
  - Xenomorphs aboard the ship may act freely, but may not attack players who have just exited cryo and are acquiring gear.
    - This restriction ends after hijack begins.
  - Xenomorphs may not attempt to reach the Almayer before planet-side deployment occurs.

  ## In-Game Rewards, Medals, and Royal Jellies
  - Rewards must be given only for valid accomplishments. The reason for each award must reflect actual contributions.
  - Awards containing insults, obscenities, or prohibited content are forbidden.
  - Players may not grant multiple identical awards for the same accomplishment — each award in a round should be tied to a unique event.
  - Awards must follow roleplay logic and the context of the round. Giving awards for inappropriate or chaotic actions is not allowed.

  # IC Communication (In Character)

  All in-game communication must reflect your role, the setting, and the atmosphere.
  This applies to all IC channels, including local chat, radios, announcements, phones, etc.

  ## General Principles
  - Modern internet slang, memes, and similar expressions inappropriate to the setting are not allowed.
  - Do not discuss game mechanics, updates, balance, or other OOC topics in IC channels. Use LOOC for that.
  - Messages should be meaningful and relevant to the situation.

  ## Caps Abuse
  - CAPS is allowed only with roleplay justification (battle shouting, panic, alarms).
  - Excessive or constant shouting without reason is disruptive and considered a violation.
  Example violation:
    - "EVERYONE TO DEPLOYMENT NOWWWWWWW!!!!!!" when "Everyone to deployment, quickly!" would suffice.

  ## Spam and Flooding
  - Spam of any kind is prohibited — repetitive, meaningless, or overly long messages disrupt communication.
  - This includes mass spam, copypasta, random characters, noise spam, and coordinated meme messages.
  Examples of violations:
    - "aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa"
    - "%$#@^!(^%"
    - "Medic here!" (repeated 10 times)
    - Meaningless chatter in IC channels at round start ("meow", "pookie", "we’re all going to die", etc.)

  ## Brainrot (OOC Slang)
  - Any use of OOC slang in IC is prohibited: "lol", "kek", "ez", "gg", "rofl", "skill issue", "afk", "xD", "thx", etc.
  - Exception: legitimate military abbreviations when used correctly in context.

  ## Hive Mind Speech
  - Hive mind communication is IC and must preserve the atmosphere of the collective consciousness.
  - Terms tied to Xenomorph mechanics are acceptable ("plasma", "shuttle", "evolution"), but meme talk, spam, and slang are not.

  ## Toxicity in IC
  - Insults are allowed when they fit roleplay, context, and are directed at characters, not players.
  - Personal attacks that target the player rather than the character are strictly forbidden.
  - If an IC conflict turns into personal hostility, it may be treated as a violation.
  - Administrators make the final judgment on acceptable aggression levels.

  Examples of acceptable IC lines:
    - A marine yelling at a Xenomorph: "Die, monster!"
    - The Queen commanding: "Destroy these foolish primates."

  Examples of violations:
    - Insulting a player directly in IC with personal or degrading remarks.
    - Using IC as a vehicle to harass a real person rather than act through character.
</Document>
