<Document>
  # Rule 2: Roleplaying
  This server has medium roleplaying expectations. Play a believable character. Treat your character as a separate entity from yourself, the player. Your character's in-game actions, feelings, and knowledge should be based solely on the character's experiences, not your own experiences as a player. Low-effort roleplay actions that are irrelevant to your character or the setting (memes, silly IC copypasta) are unacceptable. Character development can occur across rounds, but each round is a soft reset, meaning you can have prior mission experience (unrelated to Xenomorphs), but your character has never died or escaped the ship in the past. Adhere to the roleplay standards outlined below.

  Major shenanigans that could disrupt the normal flow of the round at the beginning of the round (this includes but is not limited to major or lethal fights, brawls in the briefing, riots, brig breaches, major equipment restrictions, and capturing players trying to get to their prep room) are not permitted.

  ## Human Roleplay Standards

  ## Drop Pod Arrests and Riots
  - Causing a riot on the dropship over an arrest prior to the first drop will be considered sabotage and admins will intervene and apply punishments. You should not lynch the MP's and risk your career over them arresting a marine.

  ## Sanity
  - All USCM personnel are mentally stable and physically fit for duty. They will not abandon their post or go against the USCM without due cause.
  - For example, a maintenance technician would not start cutting up bodies in a trash can.
  - The USCM is knowledgeable about most threats, including all human forces (SOF, UPP, PMCs, etc.) as well as general knowledge of the Xenomorph Hive structure.
  - The USCM command staff are not aware of the presence of a Xenomorph threat on the planet they are conducting operations on unless that information is provided in the custom deployment.
  - All personnel involved in the operation should follow their role requirements: a field medic heals others as well as themselves, a weapons specialist should take and use their equipment, and a squad leader should not ignore command orders to just do their own thing.
  - Senior squad members (e.g., Squad Leader, Specialist, Smartgunner, and SAW Gunner) should follow orders given to them by the Captain and not run off to fight alone.  Special circumstances preclude this requirement, but players should be prepared to justify their actions if contacted by staff.
  - Certain department heads (Quartermaster, CMO, and CO) should not leave the ship except under exceptional circumstances.
    - Command staff (XO/CO/Commander) should be deployed to perform command tasks, not be "special" riflemen.
    - Command staff generally should not go planetside without the Captain's permission.
  - All marines should deploy where possible, refusing to deploy because someone is arrested is unacceptable within the confines of an operation.
  - Ship crew allowed to deploy should stay in safe zones and perform their functions: - Maintenance Technicians should assist in FOB construction or securing the areas near the FOB. - Medics shouldn't be combat medics, putting themselves in harm's way to drag injured or dead marines out of combat. - The Correspondent is to document the fighting and is expected to retreat in the event of hostile engagement.

  ## Ship Modifications
  - Stripping the ship should not occur until after the first drop and confirmed contact. Marines would not immediately start tearing their warship apart over a random unconfirmed distress beacon.
    - This includes stripping things like the briefing chairs; however, this does not include barrels and crates strewn about the engineering areas.
    - This also includes unbolting vending machines from the ship where they are clearly not needed. You wouldn't drag half the contents of medbay onto the battlefield.
  - Ship modifications should not be made with metagaming purposes; you cannot build a maze or bunker on the ship that will help defend against a hijack before you even know a hijack is possible.

  ## Survivors
  - Survivors have more leeway than marines, with their mental stability due to the trauma they might have sustained during a Xenomorph attack. They can suffer from PTSD, paranoia, or similar conditions for roleplay purposes.
  - Survivors may NOT be hostile towards marines unless they are of a hostile faction.
    - Hostile survivors may not attempt to harm other survivors.
  - Survivors should not rush to attack the hive while the Xenomorphs are in their early stages; their primary goal is survival.  Most survivors have never had combat experience (unless their profession states otherwise, e.g., prison guard) and assisting the marines would not be logical.
  - Survivors cannot be assigned to enlisted, NCO, or officer tasks.

  ## Command
  - The Captain is expected to follow immutable standard operating procedure.
    - For example, you MUST hold a briefing before the operation commences and MUST make an attempt to build a defense around your primary landing zone.

  ## IDs
  - These should only be taken for roleplay reasons, such as taking a dead XO's ID to call for evac on the ship's bridge computer. If you have taken an ID or found it on a living player (or a dead player who has been revived), you should make every effort to return it unless your character has a valid reason not to.
    - You should not be granting yourself or others expanded access to areas of the ship unless there is a staffing shortage or exceptional reason.
    - You should not be issuing yourself or others (semi-)all-access IDs.
  - The death or absence of any senior staff is a valid reason to grant yourself necessary access to conduct the operation.
    - Requisitions for missing personnel is a valid reason to grant others or yourself access to supplies, etc.

  ## Language
  - Spamming chat (local or radio) with random symbols or other gibberish is considered a violation.

  ## Xenomorphs
  - Marines know what Xenomorphs are but have never encountered them. They have a basic idea of how a hive functions.  Accordingly, they're capable of coming up with and enacting a plan to counter such a threat.
  - Marines do not know there are Xenomorphs on the colony.
  - Marines do not know any specific Xeno's prefix and suffix - the most they can do is identify caste.

  ## Xenomorph Roleplay Standards

  ## Free Will
  - Xenomorphs do not have free will. They are a hive mind, and their purpose is to enact the will of the Queen and expand the Hive.
  - Xenomorphs are not friendly and will not negotiate.
    - They are not obligated to destroy synthetics and are neutral to them by default unless their behavior interferes with the Hive's expansion.

  ## Language
  - Hivemind is a translation of their thoughts into English, so words like "hydro" or "shuttle" are acceptable.  References to game mechanics like "evolve" and "plasma," for example, are permissible, but brainrot is still prohibited. Game mechanics, like "new xeno update" should be kept to LOOC chat.
  - Spamming "meow" and similar behavior in hivemind or local chat is not permitted.

  ## Marines
  - Through the hivemind, Xenomorphs know everything every other Xenomorph knows and know the basics of human equipment, they can destroy electrical equipment (APC's, SMESes, Generators, Sensor Towers and Comms Towers).
  - At the start of the round, Xenomorphs feel the human ship looming over their hive and know that human forces will be visiting the colony soon.
  - Xenomorphs do not know the names of any individual humans but may know the role they serve.

  ## Larva
  - Larva should stay within the hive and avoid the front lines.
  - If marines are about to reach the heart of the hive and there are insufficient Xenomorphs to defend it, or a Queen ready to begin a hijack, these are legitimate reasons to leave the hive as larva.
  - Larva should NOT be sneaking onto the dropship to head to the Almayer.
    - Larvae are not a scout caste and should not be searching for survivors.

  ## Queen
  - The Queen can de-evolve anyone if she wants a particular caste; however, this should make sense, having only one type of T3 does not meet this criterion.
  - The Queen cannot force Xenomorphs into a specific caste.

  ## Xenomorphs on the Almayer
  - While Xenomorphs aboard the ship can do practically whatever they want, they are not allowed to attack people who have just exited cryo and are getting their equipment.
    - This restriction does not apply after a shuttle has been hijacked.
  - Xenomorphs should not be rushing to get onto the ship before the second drop.
</Document>
