<Document>
  # Rule 9: Use of Lethal Force
  Do not attack another player without a legitimate, explainable roleplay reason that would apply in a similar, real-world scenario. A fist fight cannot suddenly escalate into a firefight. If someone is defending themselves from blatant griefing or improper escalation, the staff handling the case will determine whether and to whom punishment is assigned. Even if justified, you are still subject to Military Law.

  ## Escalation
  - Fists and MP Tools
    - MP tools (standard MP gear available in the security lockers) are not considered lethal weapons. Unless an MP is using their tools with intent to harm, you may not respond lethally.
  - Melee Weapons and Less-Lethal Ranged Weapons
  - Lethal Weapons/Chemicals Used as Weapons
    - For example: Inaprovaline overdose.
  - If at any point a fight ceases and both parties leave the area, you may not skip escalation and re-engage. What's done is done.

  ## Exceptional Circumstances
  There are exceptional circumstances that allow bypassing standard escalation.  If the circumstances are questionable, the final decision rests with the administration. These include, but are not limited to, the following situations:
  - One escape pod remains, and four people are trying to get into it.  The hive is closing in, and in desperation, you kill the marine in front of you to take their place.
  - You're on the front lines, and another marine is furious that you took one of their magazines. You are engaged in a heated firefight with the approaching hive, and their comrade attempts to disarm and wrestle you to the ground. With no barricades or safe location around you to retreat to, you shoot the marine.

  ## Injury and Risk of Life
  In instances where there is a severe threat to life, such as being beaten to near-critical condition, escalation in a linear sense does not apply. The most important part of escalation is appropriate force; this means using the situationally appropriate amount of force.  For example:
  - Being punched twice at full health is not a severe threat to your life.  It is not grounds to go nuclear and blow up your comrades.
  - Being punched twice after already being critically injured could be considered a risk to your life, and you may take appropriate action. This is circumstantial, however, and not a "green light" for any situation.

  ## Brig Breaks
  Escalation still applies when attempting to free a marine from the brig after they have been incarcerated by the Military Police.  For example:
  - You cannot use C4 or other explosives to breach the brig and free a marine, as skipping straight to lethal weaponry violates escalation rules.

  ## Field Executions
  - Whitelisted command (Executive Officer and Commander) are permitted to summarily execute any player at any time if they meet the conditions outlined in Military Law. Excessive or poorly justified field executions (e.g., beating MP's for a justified arrest) can result in removal from the whitelist.


  ## Hostile Factions
  If you are a member of a faction hostile to the USCM, this includes:
  - Colonial Liberation Front.
  - Other response teams that indicate you are hostile to the Marine Corps when you spawn.

  - You are exempt from the Use of Lethal Force rules as long as all of the following conditions are met:
  - You have not surrendered.
  - You have not willingly accepted medical aid from USCM personnel.
  - You have not changed into a uniform that conceals your affiliation.
  - You remain "consistently hostile" to USCM forces.

  "Consistent Hostility" is defined as being actively engaged with, or engaging, USCM forces as a known target.  Using subterfuge (e.g., sneaking onto FOBs, the Alamo, the Almayer, etc.) does not meet the standards to be considered "consistently hostile," as your intentions can be misconstrued by USCM forces.
</Document>
